Preliminary guide to the Karren Alenier literary papers, 1962 - 2016 MS2223
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Karren Alenier literary papers
1962-2016
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Alenier, Karren LaLonde
MS2223
29 Linear Feet
This collection contains journals, travel diaries, correspondence, poetry and short stories published and drafts, magazines, music scores, photographs, and personal papers relating to Karren Alenier's literary career. Most of the collection folders do not have dates supplied. The date range for the entire collection is 1962-2016.
Biographical/Historical note
Karren LaLonde Alenier is author of many books of poetry and winner of the 2002 Towson University Prize for Literature. Her poetry and fiction have been published in such magazines as: the Mississippi Review, Jewish Currents, and Poet Lore. "Gertrude Stein Invents a Jump Early On," her opera with composer William Banfield and Encompass New Opera Theatre artistic director Nancy Rhodes, premiered in New York City in June 2005.
In 1982 through a program sponsored by New York's School of Visual Arts, Karren spent three weeks studying with writer/composer Paul Bowles in Tangier, Morocco.
In 1995, Karren traveled to Prague to work with James Ragan on what would become her fourth collection of poetry, later titled Looking For Divine Transportation. This collection was awarded the 2002 Towson University Prize for Literature. In 1996, her third collection of poems Bumper Cars: Gertrude Said She Took Him For A Ride was published by Mica Press of Ft. Collins, Colorado. This chapbook contained a selection of her Stein poems and an early draft of Act I of Gertrude Stein Invents A Jump Early On.
Active in the American literary community, Karren has developed and managed literary programs that promote poetry. She has been involved in organizations and programs at the Folger Shakespeare Library and the Library of Congress. Since her first book of poetry was published in 1975, she has had an active role in The Word Works, a D.C. based nonprofit literary and educational organization that publishes contemporary poetry in collector's editions and presents public programs.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains journals, travel diaries, correspondence, poetry and short stories published and drafts, magazines, music scores, photographs, conference and workshop records, and personal papers relating to Karren Alenier's literary career. Most of the collection folders do not have dates supplied. The date range for the entire collection is 1962-2016.
A thorough record keeper, Alenier has amassed volumes of materials ranging from her earliest work to her most current pieces. From personal journals dating as far back as January 1st, 1962, to unpublished handwritten poems, class assignments, rejected submission for publication and fliers and posters of poetry performances, the entire spectrum of a poet's life and struggle for recognition is covered. This collection offers the opportunity to glance into the mind of a budding artist and appreciate how both inspiration and collaborative editing contribute to the creative process.
Arrangement note
Collection remains in original order of the first donation, but folder titles were organized into seven series for ease of browsing the finding aid: Journals, Drafts and publications, Correspondence, Workshops and conferences, Personal records, Publicity and marketing, and Audiovisual and digital files. Subsequent donations are processed to fit into this arrangement.
Conditions Governing Access note
The journals (series 1) are closed until June 30, 2033. The remainder of the collection is open for research.
Poetry -- Workshops; Diaries; Opera; Poetry -- 20th century; Larew, Hiram; Cavalieri, Grace; Alenier, Karren LaLonde; Writer's Center (Bethesda, Md.)
- Journals, 1962-2012; Series 1
  Arrangement
  Arranged chronologically. The Journals that have titles are in alphabetical order at the end of the list of journals.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Journals are closed for research until June 30, 2033.
  - Journal, 1962 January 01 - 1963 January 01; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Journal, 1965 January 01 - 1965 December 10; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Journal, 1974 October 24 - 1975 November 02; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Journal, 1975 November 14 - 1976 May 15; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Journal, 1976 June 19 - 1978 March 21; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Journal, 1978 March 22 - 1979 January 02; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Journal, 1979 July 07 - 1980 April 05; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Journal, 1980 March 27 - 1981 September 29; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Journal, 1980 May 08 - 1981 January 12; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Journal, 1981 July 14 - 1981 July 02; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Journal, 1981 July 19 - 1982 March 29; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Journal, 1981 June 07 - 1981 August 26; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Journal, 1981 August 27 - 1982 January 10; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Journal, 1982 July 24 - 1982 October 12; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Journal, 1983 April 02 - 1983 December 24; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Journal, 1983 April 28 - 1983 September 18; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Journal, 1982 May 03 - 1983 April 01; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Journal, 1983 December 25 - 1984 July 03; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Journal, 1984 July 04 - 1985 February 10; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Journal, 1984 September 30 - 1986 February 10; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Journal, 1985 August 12 - 1985 October 31; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Journal, 1985 November 03 - 1986 August 06; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Journal, 1985 November 17 - 1987 February 01; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Journal, 1986 August 07 - 1987 April 06; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Journal, 1987 January 03 - 1988 June 06; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Journal, 1987 April 06 - 1987 May 31; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Journal, 1987 June 01 - 1987 August 24; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Journal, 1987 August 26 - 1987 December 22; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Journal, 1987 December 23 - 1988 April 27; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Journal, 1988 April 28 - 1988 August 25; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Journal, 1988 June 08 - 1989 April 26; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Journal, 1988 August 26 - 1989 January 10; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Journal, 1989 January 11 - 1989 June 08; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Journal, 1989 May 16 - 1989 October 11; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Journal, 1989 October 12 - 1990 March 18; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Journal, 1989 October 21 - 1990 February 27; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Journal, 1990 March 20 - 1990 July 11; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Journal, 1990 July 05 - 1990 November 22; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Journal, 1990 October 27 - 1992 April 03; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Journal, 1990 November 23 - 1991 May 13; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Journal, 1991 May 14 - 1991 November 24; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Journal, 1991 November 25 - 1992 March 13; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Journal, 1992 February 18 - 1992 August 10; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Journal, 1992 August 11 - 1993 March 17; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Journal, 1992 April 20 - 1993 December 24; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Journal, 1993 March 18 - 1993 July 18; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Journal, 1993 June 24 - 1993 December 30; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Journal, 1993 December 03 - 1994 May 25; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Journal, 1994 April 26 - 1994 November 05; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Journal, 1994 May 26 - 1994 October 18; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Journal, 1994 October 19 - 1995 January 17; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Journal, 1995 January 18 - 1995 June 21; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Journal, 1995 January 30 - 1995 April 29; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Journal, 1995 June 22 - 1995 October 26; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Journal, 1995 October 30 - 1996 May 22; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Journal, 1996 May 26 - 1997 January 04; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Journal, 1996 August 03 - 1997 January 22; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Journal, 1997 January 06 - 1998 January 01; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Journal, 1997 February 03 - 2001 April 10; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Journal, 1997 October 11 - 1997 November 18; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Journal, 1998 August 26 - 1998 October 13; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Journal, 1998 January 01 - 1998 August 07; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Journal, 1998 January 10 - 1998 May 01; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Journal, 1998 July 07 - 2001 July 14; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Journal, 1999 July 17 - 1999 April 08; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Journal, 1998 August 11 - 1999 January 12; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Journal, 1999 May 27 - 2000 May 10; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Journals, 1999-2001; Series 1 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Journal, 2000 May 15 - 2000 November 18; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Journal, 2000 August 27 - 2001 October 09; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Journal, 2000 November 20 - 2001 April 04; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Journal, 2001 April 11 - 2002 February 14; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Journals, 2001-2002; Series 1 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Journals, 2003; Series 3 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Journals, 2004; Series 1 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Journals, 2004; Series 1 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Journals, 2005; Series 1 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Journals, 2006; Series 1 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Journals, 2006-2006; Series 1 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Journals, 2008; Series 1 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Journals, 2010; Series 1 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Journal, 2010; Series 1 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Journals, 2010-2011; Series 1 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Journals, 2012, undated; Series 1 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Journal, undated; Series 1 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Journal, undated; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Journal, undated; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Journal, undated; Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Journal, clippings, misc. materials, undated; Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Journal: Calvert, 1975-1976; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Journal: Cry #2, clippings, undated; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Journal: Cry #3, undated; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Journal: Cry #4, undated; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Journal: Cry #5, undated; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Development team comments, undated; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Journal: Telephone 14, undated; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - The Thursday book, 1975; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Journal: Gargoyle, undated; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Hungry Poets Cookbook journal, undated; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Journal: Mediphors, 1994; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Journal - Opera and theater notes, 2006-2007; Series 1 (Box 22)
  - Journal - Opera and theater notes, 2007; Series 1 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Journal - Opera and theater notes, 2008-2010; Series 1 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Journal: Reconstructionist, 1991; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Journal - Word Works log, 2000 -; Series 1 (Box 21, Folder 5)
- Drafts and publications, 1968-2016; Series 2
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - Aftershock manuscript, undated; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Allegory in the Chaperon, 1968; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Birmingham Poetry Review BPR no. 40, 2013 Spring; Series 2 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Compositions and papers, undated; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Contests to submit work to, undated; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Cry: outline, undated; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Dahoman Dialogue: The King Speaks, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Dahoman Dialogue: Why the Word Bird Has No Power, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Dancers Muse, misc. works, undated; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Footwork: Paterson Literary Review, 1993; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Gertrude Stein fan, undated; Series 2 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Gertrude Stein fans, undated; Series 2 (Box 16, Folder 37)
  - Gertrude Stein Opera dialogue and sheet music, 2001-2003; Series 2 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Gertrude Stein Opera fliers and reviews, 2003; Series 2 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Gertrude Stein Opera journal #1, 1997 January 12 - 2000 January 25; Series 2 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Gertrude Stein Opera journal #2, 2000 February 02 - 2001 January 26; Series 2 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Gertrude Stein Opera Playbill, 1997 April 08; Series 2 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Gertrude Stein Opera previews, 2002 March 10; Series 2 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Gertrude Stein Opera script, 2000 August 09; Series 2 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Gertrude Stein Opera sheet music early drafts, 2000; Series 2 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Gertrude Stein Opera sheet music, Act 1, undated; Series 2 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Gertrude Stein Opera sheet music, Act 2, undated; Series 2 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Gertrude Stein Opera, edited scripts, 2000 June - 2000 August; Series 2 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Gertrude Stein Opera, first performance, 1999-2000; Series 2 (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Gertrude Stein sheet music act 1, 2001; Series 2 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Gertrude Stein sheet musicm act 2, 3, 2001; Series 2 (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - Grant requests, 2001; Series 2 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Grants related to Stein opera, undated; Series 2 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Handwritten poetry, undated; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Handwritten poetry, undated; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Handwritten poetry, undated; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Israel Horizons, 1993; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Magazine: Telephone 14, 1978; Series 2 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Magazine: World Wrights, 1997-1998; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Misc. materials, undated; Series 2 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - On a Bed of Gardenias, Paul Bowles, Jane Bowles, Love, undated; Series 2 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Performance poster, undated; Series 2 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Periodicals, undated; Series 2 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Periodicals, undated; Series 2 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Periodicals, clippings, undated; Series 2 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Piano/vocal sheet music, undated; Series 2 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Poems to work on, undated; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Poetry, undated; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Poetry, undated; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Poetry, undated; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Poetry, undated; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Poetry, undated; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Poetry, Ca. 2011; Series 2 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Poetry Committees, undated; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Poetry contest: submissions, guidelines, undated; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Poetry files, undated; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Poetry files, undated; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Poetry files, undated; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Poetry files, undated; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Poetry files, undated; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Poetry files, undated; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Poetry files, undated; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Poetry files, undated; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Poetry files, undated; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Poetry files, undated; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Poetry files, undated; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Poetry files, undated; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Poetry files, undated; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Poetry Files, undated; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Poetry Files, undated; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Poetry Files, undated; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Poetry files, undated; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Poetry files, undated; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Poetry files, undated; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Poetry files, undated; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Poetry files, undated; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Poetry files, undated; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Poetry files, undated; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Poetry files, undated; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Poetry files, undated; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Poetry files, undated; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Poetry files, undated; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Poetry files, undated; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Poetry files, undated; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Poetry files, undated; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Poetry files, undated; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Poetry files, undated; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Poetry files, undated; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Poetry files, undated; Series 2 (Box 11, Folder 38)
  - Poetry files, undated; Series 2 (Box 11, Folder 39)
  - Poetry Files: Coming to the Order, undated; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Poetry Files: Coming to the Order, undated; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Poetry files: copywrite, undated; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Poetry files: Haiku, undated; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Poetry files: Japanese poems, undated; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Poetry files: Mexico, undated; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - Poetry files: periodicals, undated; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Poetry files: published essays, undated; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Poetry files: published essays, undated; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Poetry files: Readings, undated; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Poetry files: Readings, undated; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Poetry files: small format, undated; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Poetry files: The Dancer's Muse, undated; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Poetry files: Where is She Going, undated; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Poetry notebook, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Poetry, submissions, undated; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Poetry - record of submissions, 1971-1986; Series 2 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Poetry, submissions, undated; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Poetry, with comments, 1996; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Poetry, works in progress, undated; Series 2 (Box 11, Folder 37)
  - Poetry: 20th Century Swimming Lesson, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 134)
  - Poetry: A Blossoming, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Poetry: A Review of my Proceedings at the Advocate's Country Estate, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Poetry: A Slight of Hands, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 115)
  - Poetry: Amalgamations, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Poetry: America, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Poetry: Another Proposal to the Woman of "The White Dawn", undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Poetry: At 4 and 5, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Poetry: Audience After the Rain, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Poetry: Awakening, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Poetry: Ballet in Wooden Clogs, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Poetry: Baring Up, 1990; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Poetry: Bearing Up, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Poetry: Before Amber, Something Was Given, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Poetry: Beginnings, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Poetry: Beyond Comprehension, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Poetry: Black holes notebook, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Poetry: Blossom (Now, Deirdra), undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Poetry: Blue Dance Beginning, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Poetry: Bringing Up...the Obvious, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Poetry: Building, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Poetry: Bumps, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Poetry: Burrowing, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Poetry: Bursting City Limits, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Poetry: Catching the Scent, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Poetry: Chagall's Mexico, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Poetry: Cheshire Grin, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Poetry: Closed Sets, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Poetry: Cobbler, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Poetry: Coming to Order, undated; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Poetry: Coming to the Other, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Poetry: Communicating, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Poetry: Connoisseur: Quel bec ca, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Poetry: Consolation of the New Crying, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Poetry: copies, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Poetry: Correspondence with poems, undated; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Poetry: Cry, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Poetry: Cut the Fat: but keep the feast, undated; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Poetry: Death Tale (Vietnam), undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Poetry: Desperate Steps, undated; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Poetry: Destination: Halfway, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Poetry: Digger's Explanation, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Poetry: Displacement, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Poetry: Dopping U Out of Guilt, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Poetry: Du Du Liegst Mir Im, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Poetry: Encumbrances (Conversations with My Sister), undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Poetry: Energy Sources, originals, undated; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Poetry: Engages in Passing, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Poetry: Expecting the Alarm, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Poetry: Farfa "La Luna Venditrice di Raggi Solari", undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Poetry: Fecundity, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Poetry: Figuring, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Poetry: Focus Away from Insistant Fingers, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Poetry: Focusing, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Poetry: Foiling the Moths, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Poetry: From Shock, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Poetry: Garboed Brogues, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Poetry: Grandmother, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Poetry: Held Up, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Poetry: How to Tell Antonia the Hall is Not for Hire, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Poetry: In Defiance of the 2nd Law of Thermodynamics, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Poetry: In Poetic Battle, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - Poetry: Invitation, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - Poetry: Journey, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - Poetry: Kindred Kansas Wind, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - Poetry: Klee Danse, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - Poetry: Leave-giving, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - Poetry: Lessons, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - Poetry: Let Us Labas, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 67)
  - Poetry: Like Binding Chinese Feet, Advise from the Flower Woman, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 68)
  - Poetry: Little Bird excerpts, undated; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Poetry: Living with the Breaks Mechanic's List, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 69)
  - Poetry: Looking In, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 70)
  - Poetry: Mantra for the Whole, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 71)
  - Poetry: Maze, working project undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Poetry: Message from a Floating Vessel, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 72)
  - Poetry: Mimicry, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 73)
  - Poetry: misc handwritten pieces, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 150)
  - Poetry: Mother Fuck, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 75)
  - Poetry: Mother, Don't Send Your Son to the Freezer, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 74)
  - Poetry: Movies, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 76)
  - Poetry: Moving Mountains(Peru 1974), undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 77)
  - Poetry: My Father(in a chair), undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 78)